Evan Madden

(267) 314 - 7267 | evan.madden@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA 19148 GitHub: /EvMad | Portfolio: https://evmad.github.io/portfolio-one/ LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/

Technical Skills, Languages, and Applications:

MERN, GraphQL, React, Apollo Server, MongoDB, Git Bash, Node JS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, JQuery, JavaScript, JS, ECMAScript6, ES6, Handlebars, HTML, Insomnia Core, Heroku, Cloudinary, Adobe XD, vanilla Javascript, custom CSS, React Router, React in-line styling

Summary:

Evan is a web developer with a music industry background, who has recently earned a Web Development certificate from the University of Pennsylvania LPS bootcamp, and is currently completing a UX Design Certificate through Google Coursera. His primary strengths are in organizing information, resources, and people. Evan's technical strong points are in CSS frameworks, JavaScript and JS server-side extensions, as well as both relational and non-relational databases. Evan is currently pivoting his career to intersect web development with a skillset honed over a decade of managing client experience and event production.

Recent Projects:

Community Canvas

https://quiet-oasis-46946.herokuapp.com/

Community Canvas is a full stack application developed for users to upload and view photos of street art in their city and around the world. This project role focused on learning how to use Cloudinary as a digital assets management platform, and incorporating cloud capabilities into the application, as well as creating a mobile-first design and enjoyable user experience.

BandFinder

https://keith-l-watford.github.io/artists-and-bands/

This group collaboration utilizes API's from Ticket Master and the music service Deezer to provide search data on upcoming live music events by area, plus links to artist information and playlists. This project role focused on using Bulma to create a streamlined and mobile-responsive user interface, as well as handling custom CSS, JavaScript, and HTML.

Riff Lifter Touring

https://www.rifflifter.com

A new mobile-responsive site featuring a poster archive for Riff Lifter Touring, and image cards with landing pages for on-going music industry projects. Built with HTML and CSS. Currently Evan is refactoring the site into a Progressive Web Application.

Relevant Employment:

Kung Fu Necktie

March 2015-Present

- Summary: Live Music Venue in Philadelphia, PA
- Role: Bar Manager, Show Runner, Concert Promoter
- Tools: Google Calender, PrismFM, Google Sheets, Social Media
- Additional Responsibilities: ticket sales, targeted ad promotion, VIP ticket experiences

Riff Lifter Touring

Feb 2011 - Feb 2018

- Summary: Talent Booking Agency for North America
- Role: Booking Agent, Tour Manager
- Tools: Excel, Adobe Photoshop, Social Media
- Additional Responsibilities: data management, securing international work visas, managing daily tour budgets, transportation logistics

Education:

Google Coursera UX Design Certificate Program Oct 2021 - present

Web Development Certificate, BCS Coding Bootcamp University of Pennsylvania - August 2021

BA in Music, Recording Emphasis University of Maryland Baltimore County